<html>
<h1>Baby's First Game&#8482;</h1>
Baby's First Game&#8482; 1.3<br/>
Copyright &#169; 2013-2017, David J. Rager<br/>
<font color="yellow"><a href="http://www.fourthwoods.com">http://www.fourthwoods.com</a></font><br/>
<p/>
<b>Baby's First Game</b> is a game designed for kids from infants to preschool. They will have fun learning about colors, shapes,
numbers and letters. The skill levels are very customizable and can grow with your child. This game was inspired by
<font color="yellow"><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/babysmash/">Baby Smash</a></font> by Scott Hanselman and watching the games my
own kids were interested in.
<p/>
Three mini-games provide a fun way to get familiar with and learn to identify colors, shapes, numbers and letters. <b>Just for Baby</b>
is targeted specifically at infants and young toddlers. It teaches action/reaction while familiarizing baby with colors and shapes.
When baby touches the screen, a happy shape appears. <b>Find It!</b> tests your child's ability to identify colors, shapes, letters and numbers
by picking them out of a group. <b>Pop It!</b> is a fun way to work on your child's hand/eye coordination while "popping" shapes as they fly
across the screen.

<h3>Just for Baby</h3>

As your child touches the screen a random shape will appear accompanied by friendly laughter or a voice saying the color and name 
of the shape. This will help get your child familiar with colors and shapes. The settings may be adjusted to say only the color name or only the
shape name. If you like you may also add in numbers and letters as well.
<p/>
You may choose to turn off the voices and work with your child by asking them to name the color of the shape that has appeared or to name the
letter or number that has spun into view.

<h3>Find It!</h3>

Your child will be asked to find a shape among a group of shapes. As your child chooses a shape on the screen they will hear a friendly "you did it!" or encouragement to "try again".
<p/>
The easiest level asks the child to find the shape that is a particular color. The intermediate level asks to identify a particular shape from a
group of shapes. The highest level will ask the child to find a particular shape of a particular color where the shape may occur
multiple times in the group.

<h3>Pop It!</h3>

Shapes, numbers and letters jump across the screen. The goal is to pop each one by sliding your finger across the shape. In the easiest level
there is just a never ending stream shapes that just love to be popped. The intermediate level focuses on popping shapes of a specific color. For
each correct shape popped the score goes up. For incorrect shapes, the score goes down. Each game is timed with the goal of achieving the best score.
The highest level focuses on popping specific shapes, letters or numbers. Again, the score goes up for correct shapes and down for incorrect shapes.

<h3>Settings</h3>

Because different kids develop at different speeds the game is designed to be highly customizable. Adjust the settings as you wish to familiarize
your child with all shapes, numbers and letters or turn some off to focus on just a small group at a time.

<h6>Difficulty</h6>

The difficulty settings are divided into "suggested" age ranges which simply controls the challenge presented to the child. This setting has no
effect for the <b>Just for Baby</b> mini-game. For the other games this will control whether the child is asked to identify colors or shapes or
both. The difficulty can be further adjusted by enabling or disabling groups of shapes and letters as described below.

<h6>Shapes</h6>
<b>Basic Shapes</b> - This setting will present the shapes circle, square, triangle, rectangle and star.<br/>
<b>Intermediate Shapes</b> - This setting will introduce the shapes heart, oval, pentagon, parallelogram and trapazoid.<br/>
<b>Advanced Shapes</b> - This setting will introduce the shapes hexagon, heptagon, octagon, nonagon and decagon.<br/>

<h6>Numbers</h6>
<b>Basic Numbers</b> - Basic numbers will show the numbers 1 through 10.<br/>
<b>Advanced Numbers</b> - The advanced numbers include 0 and the numbers 11 through 20.<br/>

<h6>Letters</h6>
<b>Basic Letters</b> - Basic letters begin by showing the letters A through J.<br/>
<b>Intermediate Letters</b> - This setting introduces the letters K thorugh P.<br/>
<b>Advanced Letters</b> - The advanced letters include Q through Z.<br/>
<p/>
Each of the previous groups can be enabled or disabled individually to allow your child to focus on a particular group. As your child learns you can
enable more group to provide a challenge. These settings in addition to the original difficulty settings provide the ability to really tune the
game to your child.

<h6>Voice Prompts</h6>

The voice prompt settings affect mainly the <b>Just for Baby</b> mini-game. As shapes, letters or numbers appear they are accompanied by friendly
laughter or a voice saying the color and name of the shape. These settings control what names are presented.
<p/>
<b>Shape Names</b> - States the names of the shapes as they appear.<br/>
<b>Numbers</b> - States the names of the numbers.<br/>
<b>Letters</b> - States the names of the letters.<br/>
<b>Colors</b> - States the names of the colors.<br/>
<b>Laughter</b> - Plays friendly laughter.<br/>

<h6>Credits</h6>
David Rager - Design and programming<br/>
Alexis Hay - Voices<br/>
Kara Rager - Voices<br/>
Ethan Rager - Voices<br/>
<p/>
<b>Eraser Dust</b> font by <font color="yellow"><a href="http://home.earthlink.net/~ziodavino/album1_009.htm">David Rakowski</a></font>
<p/><b>Usage Permission</b> (per David Rakowski's web site):
<i>"At this point, I'm no longer interested in the care and feeding of typefaces, and am ignoring any e-mails about fonts that come my way.
Y'all may continue to do what you wish with the shareware fonts, and send money to Columbia University if you feel that is what you must
do. Me, I've got symphonies to write and cats to feed."</i>
<p/>
Special thanks to my wife Jessica for putting up with me coding instead of getting the kids in bed.<br/>
<p/>
Also thanks to Geno Burkhard for letting me borrow his recording equipment without which this game would be pretty boring.<br/>

<h6>Privacy</h6>
No information personal or otherwise is collected by this application.

<h6>EULA</h6>
You are granted a non-exclusive, non-transferable license to install and use this Application solely and exclusively for your personal use.
<p/>
You agree that you will not copy, sell, license, distribute, transfer, modify, adapt, translate, prepare derivative works from, decompile, reverse
engineer, disassemble or otherwise attempt to derive source code from the Application or content that may be presented or accessed through the
Application for any purpose.
<p/>
THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS
FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR
COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER
IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN
CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.

</html>
